the end every story begins with once
upon a time and ends with the end what
does that mean the end the end of the
stories that mean everyone just stopped
being and there is nothing else
surely not they lived happily ever after
that's often the end right they lived
happily ever after so it's not an end
right an end is not actually an end it's
it's it's some kind of a shift a change
er a line drawn under one episode so
that a new episode can begin something
like that so the notion of end is really
an opportunity for the space for a new
beginning something like that whether
these stories exist anyway in the words
on a paper on the pages of the novel
the end marks the end of the words but
the story exists in the imagination of
the reader and so the story can continue
into the new beginning and new adventure
there's being rewritten and remembered
and relived or maybe simply opened the
door for a new mode of functioning and a
new story to begin
the crossover between the
fictionalization
of beginnings and ends and stories
and that the end the six letters and a
space hammering down its somewhat
arbitrary right at the end it's it's in
yeah the because that the story is an
abstract thing in the imagination of the
author in the imagination of the reader
and so the drawing to a close of that
story is an arbitrary thing so let's try
and extend this notion of endings out
into the actual world what things end I
mean I guess individual lives come to an
end at least that's what it looks like I
mean who knows there's there's no way to
say that sure right but it seems as
though egos at least come to an end if
not the whole of our being but the ego
at least comes to an end it stops its
oblivion so end is nothingness right for
something to end it must actually stop
and become nothing the end is an
absolute negation of what came before
maybe an end can just be a disruption a
space to start something new
potentially every closing of the eyes
that happens automatically is the end of
that vision of the world
every time I open my eyes again
I'm seeing something new like a
heartbeat new beginnings with every end
of the closure of the eyelids
you
so why even have this notion of endings
if it is in fact just the new beginning
why even have this notion of endings why
is it not a a new becoming or something
like that it's a it's is the more this
goes on the more I'm actually troubled
by the very concept of end itself why do
we even have this concept in our
language because it seems to me that
transformation is there is is is is
actually what's going on here right is
not an ending it's just a stage it's
just a step on the road and so yeah
what's what starts to feel really
interesting is why we even have this
concept in our language if it bears no
connection to what actually happens in
reality death maybe marks our
susceptibility to
permanence of ending especially in
sanitized societies where death is
something so distant and yet to be
feared I am the end in language when
language is a very binary the human
brain has a binary need or at least a
categorical need so binary is easily
accomplish that so we have beginning and
end but as soon as we get into
complexity those binary is often break
down and become symbiotic so it's really
interesting why the end is so prevalent
in language mmm it occurs that the end
of things makes more sense if you
restrict yourself to the physical realm
you can have the end of a road right you
can have the end of a room the end of a
room is marked by a wall or a door you
know the end of the road is if there's
just no more Road right and so in in the
physical world I think it possibly can
reach it so maybe the end is the
boundary between what is manifest and
what is yet to be manifest right and so
it is it is potentially transformative
because there is always more coming
there is always a future about to arrive
and yet yeah this
there's something that you could build
more Road right so it's not the end of
the road in a permanent sense but it's
the end of the right it hasn't been
built yet which raises the idea of what
about ends that happen in our minds
beliefs the end ideologies that and no
longer ascribe T and religions that are
lost
identities that are reforged and
rebirthed so the old identity ends
again there's this need in the word for
end to make it a very clear-cut divide
before and after whereas usually
transitions are not dumps there is a
zeitgeist that leads up to them it's say
it feels as though all of those examples
of religions and personal transformation
and changes of ideology and shifts in
paradigm they are transformations then
they're not you know that the the new
personality is built on top of the old
one you know it's not a complete it's
not like the old one has been completely
pushed away and an entirely new one has
been inserted it has been transformed
right healing has taken place
transformations taking place deeper
understanding has taken place more
embodied sense of being in the world has
taken place whatever it might be but
that but it is it is a transformation
under the and the memory of what was
before is is still alive so it's not
ended in the sense that it no longer
exists in any way because there the
access to the feeling of it the access
to the memory of it is is still there so
it's not it's not lost to there
decisiveness of those words and it's a
new attitude a new mode of function so
if the end is easier to understand in
Geographic or spatial terms the road the
room the immediate tangibility of my
being and a wall that blocks me and how
that transcribes to thee imagined or
idealized realm how then do we stop
seeing these shifts and so categoric the
idea of paradigm shifts
and incommensurability usually shifts
happen when there's a crossover and a
building and a growing